Wash It
All Away
Episode 2  We're Proud of Our Natural Hot Spring
Complete Your Meal!
Using 100%
Japanese Seaweed
Stick Type
In Ready-to-Eat Servings
Aoki Bakery
Cheese Bread
White Bread
Danish Bread
Walnut Bun
Cranberry &
Custard Bun
Raisin Bread
Cinnamon Roll
Anpan
Fig Bun
Cream Bun
They all look so good.
Can I have one cranberry and
custard bun and a salt pizza, please?
Oh! Hello, Kinme-san!
I've got some clothes to give you.
Is now all right?
Oh... Mm...
Sorry to catch you on your lunch break!
It's all right!
Caught me off guard.
Kinme Cleaning
Orders will be ready
on the 23rd
Hello, this is Kinme Cleaning.
Hello? This is Ishimochi calling.
Oh, Ishimochi-san? Nice to hear from you.
So it seems you let my Kyu borrow
an umbrella the other day. Thank you!
Oh, not at all. I'm sorry
I only had one with the shop logo.
I should have him thank you himself.
Hey, Kyu! Get your butt down here!
No, really, it's fine!
You sure?
Anyway, will they be ready tomorrow?
I'll bring your umbrella
when I go pick them up.
Oh. Actually, I realize it's a bit early,
but your items are ready now.
Why don't I bring them to you later today?
I can pick up the umbrella
while I'm at it.
Oh, would you really?
Sorry for the trouble.
No trouble at all. I have to make
my evening delivery run anyway.
I'll see you then, all right?
We Pick Up and Deliver!
Kinme Cleaning
Guesthouse Inn Ishimochi
Phew.
Good evening! It's Kinme Cleaning!
Hi!
Kinme-san, thanks for
going out of your way.
Could you just leave them by the door?
And your umbrella's over there.
Oh, sure!
Here's that Doburoku I was talking about.
You're gonna love it!
Yeah, thanks.
You need some more rice, boys?
How about more miso soup?
Sure, I could use seconds.
Just miso soup for me.
Comin' up.
Oh! He still hasn't thanked her.
Kyu! Get your butt down here!
Ah, that's really all right!
I need to get going anyway.
I'm sorry for bothering you during dinner.
Kinme-san, I bet you're drenched in sweat.
While you're here, why not take
a dip in our hot spring?
Yes, but I...
I'm not a paying customer...
Aw, it's fine!
We're just a small inn, but we're sure
proud of our natural hot spring!
I have so much trouble
resisting temptation.
But I guess I am done
with work for the day.
Might as well enjoy!
Kinme-san!
Ah! Yes?
When you get out,
you can go cool off on the roof.
Thank you very much.
Caught off guard again!
So are you Kyu, then?
Actually, my name is Kyusho.
Oh, got it.
I bet you get a lot of reservations
for days with fireworks shows.
You've basically got front-row seats.
Yes. We get booked up far in advance.
Atami
Seaside Fireworks Show
A Symphony of Fireworks Painting the Sky with Seasonal Colors
Spring
Summer
Fall
Winter
Please help us keep your trip to Atami safe and comfortable.
Some regulars already have reservations
for every event from now to February.
Wow, really?
February? That's got to be
more than ten shows.
It is.
Are those guests
staying tonight also regulars?
Well, those men are here
for a construction job.
They've been staying for about two weeks.
Two weeks?
Guesthouse Inn Ishimochi
We're a small inn, but we're inexpensive,
so we get all sorts of guests.
Sometimes we even get foreign backpackers.
Huh. No kidding.
But our bath is pretty great.
We're just a small inn, but we're
real proud of our natural hot spring.
Your mother seems like
a very generous hostess.
More like annoying when
you're stuck in a family with her.
That still sounds nice.
I wish I had family members
that were annoyingly close.
You do?
I can't even remember
if I had any family at all.
My memory only goes back two years.
It seems I washed
all my older memories clean away.
Oh! But I'm okay!
I don't really worry about it.
Huh? O-Okay.
A-Anyway, I don't want to overstay
my welcome, so I should get going.
I hope you still remember
what I asked before.
Your schoolbag.
My schoolbag.
Do you think you could clean
my schoolbag for me sometime?
Sure! You can count on Kinme.
Guesthouse Inn Ishimochi
I mean, her memory seems fine to me.
Kyu! Don't forget to scrub
the bath when you're done.
Wash It All Away
It's been pretty quiet all day. It seems
like things are settling down again.
I guess we're almost over the hump of
people sorting through winter clothes.
I should think about making a new
batch of flyers to pass around.
Nairo, it is all right if you want to
go on ahead to meet Grandmother.
No, I'll go with you
like it's a school field trip.
Oh, please come in.
Good afternoon.
Good afternoon to you!
Wow, she's so pretty.
Good afternoon.
Good afternoon!
She's so cute!
Is this your first time visiting us?
Yes. My friend told me about your shop.
I hear that you are very skilled
at removing stains,
so I thought I'd ask for your help.
Thank you very much! I'm flattered!
Our motto here is
"Local Cleaning with a Heart."
In addition to clothing,
we clean shoes, of course,
but also other kinds of
accessories, leather or fabric.
Also, while we do have a limited range,
with just a call, we'll go straight to
your home for pick-up and delivery—
a service particularly appreciated by
elderly members of the community.
At any rate, please allow me
to inspect your garments.
Go right ahead.
Oh. It appears to have
something splattered on it.
That's squid ink pasta sauce
from dinner last night.
There also appears
to be something drawn on.
A meat bun?
I know! I can explain it to you!
That's my favorite place in the world!
Saint Basil's Cathedral!
You see, my daughter simply loves to draw.
She seems to have been inspired when
the squid ink splattered on the blouse,
so she stuck her finger
in the sauce and then drew that.
It is all so embarrassing.
I am very sorry.
Well, it happens!
Maybe she's not so cute?
Um, do you think
you'll be able to clean it?
You can count on Kinme.
Hey, Mother?
I want to learn how to
get stains out of clothes!
Oh? But what about visiting Grandmother?
I will go by myself later.
In that case, go and ask the nice lady
if it's all right to observe her at work.
Mm-hmm!
Onee-san!
Would you please let me
observe you working?
Okay, yes,
she is cute!
Of course!
Oh, oh, oh!
What is that stuff you are painting on it?
Oh, this?
This is a stain treatment
designed to break down oils.
Fabric
Dye
Protein Stain
Tannin Stain
Water-Based Stain
* The composition of
each stain is different,
but this is essentially
how stains attach to fabric.
Oil-Based Stain
The Structure of a Stain
There is a standard procedure
to follow when removing stains.
First, you break down
the oily part of the stain,
and then you use different solvents to
wash out the other parts one by one.
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
Field Trip
Cleaners
A lady named
Kinme-san manages
the shop by herself.
Remove oil from
a stain first.
Lots of detergents.
Hmm. So you use more than
just one detergent, I see.
How did you learn so much
about detergents and stain removal?
Hmm. Good question.
How did I learn all of this?
I guess it's a mystery.
Huh?
Field Trip
Cleaners
A lady named
Kinme-san manages
the shop by herself.
Remove oil from
a stain first.
Lots of detergents.
How she learned it
is a mystery.
Huh?
Oh! Oh, oh!
Whoa!
What is that thing?
Well, this shoots out steam.
If you steam the spot where
you applied the stain remover,
it helps to release the stain.
And while you're doing that, the stand
here sucks the stain out from below.
It really works! It sucked it out!
And then...
See? The stain is almost gone.
Wow! Amazing! It's like magic!
This stain is still only a day old,
so it isn't that stubborn yet.
So after this, we'll soak it in bleach
for a while and it should be good.
I want to try removing stains too!
Huh?
No, no! I know this looks easy,
but it's actually very delicate work.
This is something
only professionals should do.
But I would love to spray the steam!
Pretty please, Kinme-oneesama?
I promise to be a very good girl!
I will do anything you say!
Well, all right.
But we can't have you
handling customers' garments,
so you can work on one of my old towels.
Nairo-chan?
One moment, please.
Oh!
Thank you for waiting.
I drew a stain on my shirt!
She might not be cute after all!
I did it!
It's so clean, it's so clean.
The towel has got so clean.
I'll have to wash this later by myself.
It's so clean. And I did it!
Thank you for lending me this shirt
and for everything else today!
You're welcome. Just return that when
you come to pick up your laundry, okay?
Okay!
Next time I come, please let me assist you
with cleaning customers' clothes too.
Uh, well...
I appreciate the offer, but I don't think
you're ready for that yet, Nairo-chan.
Huh?
If you want to do a good job of
taking care of other people's clothes,
you have to learn how to take
good care of your own clothes first.
I believe that when clothes
are taken good care of,
they fill up with their owner's
life stories and memories.
They turn into treasures.
I don't have any memories
of my own past at all.
That's why I want to help people take care
of their treasures as long as they can.
I'm...
Any time you want to learn more about
cleaning, come back and visit me. Okay?
Okay!
Nairo-chan, huh.
She does seem to be a nice,
polite girl at heart.
Well, then. Shall we get washing?
Is this the place?
Smells delicious!
Atsuei Dried Fish Company Direct Sales
Atsuei Gift and Souvenir Shop
Um, excuse me, please.
Well, hello there.
I have dried horse mackerel
hot from the grill for just 250 yen.
Oh! I actually received a call
this morning for a laundry pick-up.
I'm from Kinme Cleaning.
Is this Katakuchi-san's residence?
Yes, that would be me.
But what phone call? And a pick-up?
Huh?
Oh! You really came, didn't you?!
Nairo-chan?
See, Grandmother? This is Kinme-oneesan.
Oh my! Thank you for
watching over Nairo the other day.
Not at all. So is this store...
Yes! This is my grandmother's gift shop!
There's no school today,
so I came here to help out.
Oh? How sweet of you, Nairo-chan!
Tee-hee.
Um... Does that mean
the phone call this morning...
Yes!
I imitated Grandmother's voice
and called you myself!
I wanted to ask you to clean
some things from her shop.
I knew something was off.
This is what I'd like you to clean.
Celebrating a Big Catch
Atsueimaru
Katakuchi Uretaro
It's lovely.
My grandfather was a fisherman. He flew
this banner when he got a big catch.
Atsuei Dried Fish Company Direct Sales
They used to keep it hanging
at the entrance to the shop,
but it started to get too dirty,
so they eventually brought it inside.
That's what Grandmother told me.
Grandmother tried to send it out
for washing several years ago,
but the cleaners refused to wash it.
I can see why.
It's a one-of-a-kind banner
that a fisherman used for years.
If you wash it too harshly, you're likely
to damage or tear the aging fabric.
Do you think you can wash it for us?
"You can count on Kinme"
is what I would usually say, but please
allow me to borrow it for a while first.
I'd like to take a closer look before
I decide if it will be possible to clean.
Is that all right with you?
Yes, all right.
I will let my grandmother know.
Oh, there's also...
an apron and a bandana...
and this curtain and that lap blanket...
and some seat cushions
I would like you to wash!
All right.
There might be more, so I'll go ask.
Uh, okay!
Grandmother!
Will it all fit?
Atsuei Gift and Souvenir Shop
Atsuei Dried Fish Company Direct Sales
Gift Shop
Atsuei Dried Fish Shop
Grandmother, should we
send that to get cleaned too?
Hmm... I suppose so.
Okay!
Um, are you sure it's okay to take your
noren curtain down during business hours?
Oh, it's fine.
Anything to keep Nairo happy.
Here you go, honey. Enjoy.
What? U-Uh...
But I'm still on the clock right now.
Mmm! So fatty and delicious!
Here, please wash this too.
Hmm? Uh, okay. One second.
There's no rush. Please take your time.
Thank you very much. That was delicious!
Even though I'm still working,
I just couldn't resist.
Thank you. Please take care of our things.
Thank you, dear.
My pleasure. I'll contact you
sometime tomorrow about the banner.
I'll be on my way, then.
Take care!
Thank you!
Men's Bath
Women's Bath
I didn't expect to get
such a big order today.
Do you come here often?
Recently, it's only when
Nairo comes to spend the night.
Is that right?
I used to come more often when
my husband was still alive, though.
But you know, that silly man,
he actually hated the bath.
Whenever he came with me, I couldn't
relax and enjoy myself like I do now.
Huh? Did Grandfather
really hate the bath that much?
Yes. During wintertime,
he'd wait outside and yell to me,
"Hurry up and get out! It's too cold!"
I absolutely love the bath!
That's right, Nairo.
You just love baths, don't you?
This one is even more fun
than the bath at home!
Is that right? Lucky you.
Have a good night!
Good night.
Atsuei Dried Fish Company Direct Sales
Nairo's grandmother
must really treasure that banner.
Translation:
Editing and Typesetting:
Michael Arnold
Ashley Barboza
Quality Control:
Translation Check:
Riley Dalton
Sriram Gurunathan
Episode 3 We Are Closed for the Day
Next time is "We Are Closed for the Day."